welcome to my clothes lab come on in I
moved to San Diego five months ago from
Phoenix Arizona and my goal was to build
the ultimate glute lab and I finally
finished the gym it's complete and I
can't wait to show off all my pieces of
equipment so let's get started this here
is my private Gloria this is a scorcher
I built this in 2006 wheezed in my gym
lives which was in Scottsdale and then
it's sat dormant for the last decade and
now I'm very happy to unveil it here
here's how it works we use long band for
resistance you'll pull this up climb
underneath it through her hips and then
put your feet up here sink down get into
place and then the bands are pulling
down whether you seek way down thrust up
against the resistance we just single a
table here but we also do bad resisted
and we love all different types of bands
as you can see here of the bands from
sore necks bears from romance from elite
up TS got a million of big ones small
ones and everywhere in between over here
we've got our heavy dumbbells these are
from rogue I got one 30s and one 50s
Buse is my cat about collection I got a
106 pounder I got 157 I got a two or
three pounder this is more like a
cannonball and these are my center mass
belts from sore necks these are hundred
gondor's 70 35 these are like dumbbells
but they're just different they feel
you need to feel I love them this here
is the cable column that I got from
sword X what I love most about this is
that it's got a 250 pound weight staff
but it's got these band pegs for added
resistance and as you can see here and
all these different short bands that I
can use to really load it up we do a lot
of things off of this we use this guy
this is an IPR kickback of attachment
this goes around the ankle and we'll do
different types of kickbacks there's
four different types of kickbacks with
you this time here is a spud off we will
loop this around the waist connected to
the column we will kneel right down here
do these guys sink back and perform
kneeling hip thrusts against resistance
this is a favorite right now with our
glute squadrons we also have single
handles for lateral raises the rope for
cable pull through we even have wrist
cuffs so you can do things like rear
delt raises and exercise without using
the hands my dumbbell rack I got
dumbbells all the way to the hundreds
got an adjustable bench here obviously
we use this for things like dumbbell
incline chest supported rows and the
like here I've got a bunch of gadgets
and I use every one of them that the
stability ball I got these point stands
I don't use this for a little bit weight
lifting I use these pulling stands to
stand on top of and we will hold on to a
dumbbell this way and perform dumbbell
between bench squats but I'll split this
up wider and also use this guy here
which is a loading pan in a cedar I'll
handle and I'll load this up with 45
pound plates or 25 I've got women
performing this extrapolate that's what
it's called this traveler and you see
it's like a
between the dirt and his squad what I
can like it too is the hex bar deadlift
yep you got a wider stance and it's
going in between your legs
you need is the point in the lugging pin
and a cedar I'll handle this is my
equalizers we use this for infrared rows
you see my sled this is from rope this
spuds nice because you push it all the
way down the track once you get to the
end you just move these bars I just made
a video on this and put it on Instagram
this is my doing yourself self spotting
blueprint or front pump bar
I like loading the partner with 25 pound
plates so you have tension all the way
at the bottom when you use 45 pound
plates sometimes you don't have tension
you your hips come up and there's no
tension until you get a few inches off
the ground this solves that because you
lay down on the ground
he thrusts up you turn these out and
then you pump away then when you're done
you come up I turn the bag and set it
down
I made this with just some stuff from
Home Depot very effective this is a 80
pound preloaded bar we use this with a
squat sponge we use this to perform knee
banded barbell glute bridges we do 3
sets of 30 with our legs the 80 count is
so you thirty reps and kind of any
Remy's and this under nips and it works
great
this is my plumber box and I don't need
this reply as I actually use it for high
step-ups
as you can see it's very hot yep I'm
dealing what's the one who's shorter
we're just not as fit I don't really use
a step here to adjust for that and I did
put risers on it if I want this is my
BOSU ball I do not use it for unstable
exercise I actually use it as a pillow
for frog bumps and glute bridges put my
head right here while I do bridge in
front pump away and finally we've got
the glue Hamm roller from sore necks and
with this you lay down you put your
heels here sort of like a slight board
or valslide late girl but it's even
nicer because you got rollerblade wheels
it's really smooth this is the spot
skiing I will use this for handles for
the cable kneeling spots but we can also
use this for squats and military press
and things like that this is my pulldown
station you know this is the traditional
handle which will discipline a tit
formated
i've also the attachment here my
attachments this is my favorite the wide
neutral grip this is the mag this is
like a medium Pro slightly pronated grip
this is a like an EZ bar style for like
triceps or V bar for triceps seated row
handle this is narrow neutral we also
use this for polio and single hand /
single arm pull down two more single
handles
sometimes we combine these so you can
spread them and then I got a few unique
ones this is from fun and
extra-wide you hold on it like this and
do different types of face pulls and
Rosie can spread it out as he do him and
this for my friend Smitty this is
something similar to that just not quite
as wife was nice as you can hold it like
this this is very heavy-duty and this
guy's my favorite it says metal metal
handles it's very sturdy and I do a new
face bulls and roses these guys love it
so those are all my attachments before
the pull down on cable : got my incline
press we pretty much just do include
press off of here
but my tip stand it serves as a the
storage for bands but we do give some
weighted dips off of here and then I
also got my weighted vest which you can
use for squats and lunges and push-ups
and pull-ups and things like that
there are about different types of
inhalation so these are the lighter
ankle weights these are ten pounders and
these guys are twenty pounders well I
use the twenty pounders a lot of my
women I use the Condors with ankle
weights we do a lot of abduction work we
also will use it here for stealing
creamer ciphers which is especially
well-suited for restoring gluten
balances single like ankle weight
reverse diapers this is my seated
shoulder press bench I do barbell
dumbbell and smith machine shoulder
press off of that also seated lateral
raises this is my Riverside Bronco just
from Westside many
years ago we do bilateral and unilateral
reverse diapers this with the pendulum
we also will pull this up and have
clients climb underneath and they kneel
on the pad pulled onto the rails and
then they do kickbacks so you can do a
kickback when you actually extending the
knee and then a bent leg when you're
coming up more and the ladies love this
exercise for glutes this is my chest
before tomorrow this is from Atlantis
it's got three grips neutral and and
slightly promet pronated 45 degrees and
more protonated as you can see I'm tone
of 45 complaints here I didn't want to
have to go looking for 45 so I've got a
million of them
this here is my 45 degree hyper we use
this for body way 47 hours dumbbell
barbell band we can put bands around
this guy and put a band around the torso
around the neck and single leg doubling
and any combination thereof this is very
well used here so is this lever squad
tough stuff made this years ago they
don't make anymore we do mainly squats
and in verse 11 but we also do calf
raises off of them calf raises squat so
easy to teach I've met many muscle
activity not much different than regular
squat even in the stabilizer muscles now
this area is a rogue power rack and I
got all the bells and whistles I got a
really tall one for that reason I
actually
the military chin up bar upside down
because it was too tall for people but
you can do neutral soup supinated and
pronated pull-ups off of their rings and
we perform inverted rows of these but
this works nicely
if I wanted a rose because I'll just lay
back here and put my feet on there this
is a single leg squats did we do
Bulgarian split squats often here but
actually we use the thruster more often
to perform or gear in split squats it's
just such a nice so nice off the hip
dresser but I can do them there too
obviously we do squat and good morning
and lunch variations here you've got
these guys here for band attachments
those we will put these like this one on
each side to hold on to and put the
safety squat bar on which is over here
I'll go over a minute and you can do
safety bar safety bar half-filled squats
where you're holding on here because
with the safeties box pop are you don't
have to hold on so we give you squats
and lunges while holding on so you can
use a lot of weight here I got the
jammer handles if we're using this we're
going to take the step-up platform off
but here you know standing presses which
are awesome you can also perform
different rowing movements with it
standing then we got to step up
attachment now I can put this from any
height we can use dumbbells body weight
whatever sometimes we'll even have the
Rings here you can use the Rings to
perform single leg squats with the Rings
but you can also do this system step
downs with the Rings we would shorten
them up obviously and then you just
as low as you can we've got the box what
I got this from elite elite up TS many
years ago this goes from 11 is 16 inches
it's a staple for teaching the squat
this is my hip thruster station got the
greatest set up first of all I got a
squat sponge here this is needed if you
want to have ample protection on the
hips but I also have extra mat these are
an inch and a half thick and these are
crucial because when you're sitting and
you roll the bar over see this you need
this added room to get the bar
comfortably on the hips and then also
the height is 15 inches which is thirty
five point five centimeters is an ideal
height for the masses now if I have a
really tall person it works fine if I
have a really short person or just
someone with a really short torso
relative their overall height I will put
this guy here this is an air expelling
spatter don't sit on it and that
effectively most of my players so
they're changing from lower on the back
they do Barbara up this of all ranges in
here we also do a lot of band interest
will perform hip family get dressed
a rush it all the band's way over there
so these will connect from here to here
and then people can do it's us against
bands we also will combine the bands the
hip bands any bands for the knees I got
so many of these different types of
minivans of God all these different
types of hip circles and these of
different sizes and strengths this guy
is really heavy-duty here we've got
lighter ones these you wear right above
the knees some people like below the
knees while you do have thrust we
actually use these all the time for a
lot of different exercises you can use
it with Davos Platz you can use them
with bridges and frog bumps and hip
press we also use these for lateral band
walks similar ones monster walks they're
seated hip abductions being
introductions and about 10 other awesome
like lambs and things like that we also
have this regular rubber mini bands or
loops of different sizes and strengths
real light you can put these on the
Bubba knees below the knees around the
ankles around the feet and then we've
got these guys which are very strong
these are short bands from sore necks
and we love these of all different sizes
and strains what we do with these is we
will put this around the barbell here
and then I'll loop it around here like
this and so it's connected to the bar
then as you get the rest up this
stretches and when I got these on the
bar it adds a lot of weight and this is
my favorite way to hip thrust is using
these guys with the barbell so let's say
I have two plates on the bar and then
this guy it might be 225 at the very
bottom but it might be 500 pounds at the
top you can also wear a hip circle
nominees while you do that that we call
a triple band interest is you got two of
these guys and one of these it also be
single I get thrust we also do feet
elevated bridges where we actually put
the band's here and then you lay your
torso here and you put your feet here
and you thrust against the resistance
lots of versatility out of the hip
thruster this also has pegs here if you
want to do band resisted dead lifts you
can stand here and do demos this is my
deadlift platform and this has been pegs
see here so you can drink bands over the
bar this is a Texas deadlift bar and we
can put bands over a new band resisted
Douglas especially like band resisted
speed others along here we do lots of
fifth leg deadlifts wagon-wheel death
here are my clips clips and colors now
here I got all these cool attachments
really proud of these this here is my
Viking press attachment this is used for
the land mine to do neutral grip
shoulder presses and I miss my like this
more than I like military presence I
actually jump with this guy which is an
adjustable weight line unit that you can
put in the rack I'll put this up high in
Iraq and I use it with my Viking press
and it feels amazing this you use with
the way in line and you perform bent
over rows it's so smooth it feels great
I got this for broke I got this from
rogue as well this he also used with the
landmine and this actually feels like a
seated row but you do with the barbell
we need dip belts for ups and dips
this one we don't use this much because
cable point stations this you can hook
into a power rack if you train out in a
garage tricep work and things like that
this is a deadlift jack weighs one pound
this was made by my friend Steve clever
it's so nifty you can keep this in your
gym bag Jack one side of the bar up and
then take the plates off finally I've
got my SWAT wedges these are got off
Amazon we just use these to elevate
people's heels they put their heels up
here and make some squat more upright
where you can combine them to do two of
them people put their heel here and they
do goblet squats or whatever off of this
and it works like a charm very effective
teaching tool for squads if you want
people to be more upright
this is my death lever and my chalk did
I got this chocolate when I was first
starting out because I was so sick of
letting go the bar while i debit did
yes I found adds like 80 pounds to my
grip during Dennis just having nice
chocolate here I've got my little plates
my five calendars my to nap downers in
my fractional plates this was important
because I got to a point where I was so
sick of sliding plates off I said never
again I'm gonna Jack the war up for dead
list and get dressed
is this a grappler that I got from West
Side now this is cool because you just
use it as a regular by my unit but you
got two of them so if I have two
barbells I give you a lot of raises with
the two barbells or I can do these
grappler now exercise we're not the two
bars and I'm going on this it's a crazy
effective rotational abdominal exercise
here I got the Smith machine I bought
this Smith machine so I could do him
throw us up I just love the feeling of
Smith machine him for us but this is
slightly angled I think I do prefer the
vertical ones that I got a good deal on
this so with the angled hip thrust a
funny you want the bench on this side so
it's angled this way it's a little bit
easier on my pelvis that way we do a lot
of Smith machine hip thrusts and it's so
easy because you just love the plates up
right here boom it's so smooth you start
from the top down this is a Hampton
thick bar pattern so the bar pattern was
focused at the pump as air expands they
all work great we do reverse lunges off
the hero
as well sometimes we do smith machine
shoulder press things like that this is
a glute/ham developer I got from elite
FPS I've use this thing for probably 15
years it's still sturdy and I love it as
you can see Dan peg attachments here we
do bodyweight we do band we do dumbbell
as resistance you can sit up here and
face upwards and do straight leg sit-ups
you can do Gutierrez's you can move this
back and get back extensions or you can
perform my favorite which is an
in-between so it could come combination
of blue hand raises and dark extensions
called the inverse curl and that's an
exercise most people don't know about
that's my favorite hand exercises this
is my benchpress station is such a nice
get to unit but we got the tongue tip
back down here this is a thicker and
wider pad and it's just really nice for
dudes who have shorter issues it spares
their shoulders a lot of guys have
fuller issues they start bitching on
stuff and they go away I think it
teaches me how to use my lats more and
have a better bar pass and also have two
around ten pounds of my bench press
which is nice we also got the 2-part
here if you want to work one top in
Smith we've got the slingshot this is
Mark Bell creation and this you put
their arms through here put your arms
through these sleeves and so it
stretches here so as you go down into
bench this stretches and it assist you
at the bottom so you got the assistance
you can use more weight but you got to
take over at the top so Philips lockdown
strength we also got these James but I
can also I could use these chains for
squats deadlifts bench management and I
love it for all overloading the top ring
bench press but also forgets technique
training what you'll find is the other
just a better bark up with when you use
chains let me go over some of my
cabinets I got here
push up handles push ups in that strange
factors these are the iron all really
really fat gripz you can put this on a
chin-up bar or on dumbbells or a barbell
strengthen your grip these are fat gripz
that will probably roll outs out Matt I
like doing crunches and side crunches
off of these and then rippers when over
my dead left starts failing I started
using these grippers I deal them about
three times and my grips back up to full
stranger you wouldn't think they'd
transfer the deadlift but they do this
here is my belt squat and they're
different types of belt swap models
there's more cable models and there's
more like pendulum models I was with the
pit shark just because I like it I like
all of them but I like about the picture
gets to it it's just a really nice this
around your compressive loading on the
spine this is the salt air runner this
is a stop treadmill you can run you can
sprint you can either do power drills
like this where you go
so
you like this guy coming back around to
my specialty bars I've got all these
nice barbells this is the bio test dead
squat bar I just love the finish on this
looks so cool that's badass
they're a neural grip it's very white
see this this is allows it to be
racquetball he can perform pecs park
tennis with trap bar down this way we
would call it but you can also do them
out of the rack with less range of
motion feel like a stun using this Texas
power bar is a standard trap bar X bar
this here is a like King number a bug
it's got a football power Swiss bar but
it's for neutral grip bench press or
shoulder press this is a racquetball
cambered bar and this is cool for squats
and good mornings and even things like
surgery carries over here we've got the
circus flat bar this I mentioned earlier
it's nice about the safety squat bar if
you could put this over your shoulders
you can't have a wrist injury elbow or
shoulder injury you just drape it over
the balances so you can do squats
without your hands good even if you have
full functioning of your upper body
because it's really hard
it makes squatting harder it's vital for
anyone I was up for about injuries
distinct you can stay squatting to a
good mornings during lunges and then
this here's this bar this is a move
barbell and this is cool because there's
no back to it so I can go heavy here and
do reverse lunges and the like and not
worry about underneath anything and then
finally we got the Buffalo bar as you
can see this as a slight camber to it so
the curved so the use of doing bench
press you get to go a little bit deeper
it's makes benching harder but also you
can use it for squatting for guys who
have limited short external rotation
mobility these are my specialty bars
here I've got this now these are my DC
blocks and I can use these for things
like block pulls but I don't use these
much because I've got the wagon wheels
over here these are my risers for the
step-up we don't use these
so I make my own seal ruff station and
these are Sierra's I will use dumbbells
Laurie can use a barbell with these but
you just go like this so I can do chest
supported rows and a 45 degree angle
over there or horizontal over here this
is my side max squat press this is the
best leg press there is it's so
comfortable it's like the designer had
the best intuition about the human body
this thing is so smooth and comfortable
we do bilateral leg press and single leg
leg press office is my speed at hip
abduction machine works very well really
targets the glutes we can have people
lean back be straight up or lean forward
when they lean forward with a hold onto
the rails here and lean we also will
overload the eccentric component will
there come out so they'll come out like
this and then we will push this way you
have them when this eccentric way and
then I've got my
Hormats blue hair raised we use this to
perform Nordic ham curls see we're
getting it like this and then lower your
body weight under control
to perform he said overloaded knee
flexion we also will stand above the
person with a band I'll put a banner on
my back up and around the person's torso
so they can do band assisted Nordic
Ambrose here we've got all these types
of bands with handles
and I used to think these were wimpy but
I actually love them now I do a lot of
upper-body work just to add in some
extra volume for example here's the
Lowery's can stand here and just bust
out 30 reps of laterals and this is
crucial before a selfie because you'll
pump up your delts and traps and look
down at these are my wagon wheels this
is another Marvel creation so by row the
whole point of these is that they're
bigger plates so if you get lift off of
these you're gonna do block pulls you'll
set up up high no neat blocks you're not
going to use blocks for the block pulls
or you don't have to do that on the rack
you just can use these plates plus they
just look badass I've got all these
thruster benches up here this is for our
group training when you want to train a
lot of glutes at one time we'll get all
the ladies doing hip thrusts and
different all these different types of
hip thrusts and glute exercises off with
these guys they're super light they
weigh next to nothing I got these
grappling mats my trainers are really
into jiu-jitsu and they like grappling
so I got these mats and a heavy bag I
also got a bunch of mitts in the closet
and other fighting materials
I got a pair dying right here for
conditioning and a constant tuo'er so we
can use the assault air runner the
Schwinn airdyne or the concept to rower
for conditioning or combine them all for
a crazy protocol those are tough battle
ropes up here and their little aerobic
step risers just the little guys know
this door lead outside I got a parking
lot there where we can do different
strongman stuff here I got my hubby with
bunch of binders for my workouts we got
these lounges these people want to hang
around well throw this in the corner up
against the wall and they can just
chillax
I've got closet here we've got all these
different mints and punching stuff
microwave refrigerator little gadgets
and we got some things that make the
glute lab unique I can expose the duct
work so it's got a nice unique modern
look to it
and also exposed to concretely like
seeing the bricks that makes it less
unique look to it I got the astroturf on
the side there I can think I should have
put it in the middle live and learn
either way it looks cool when people
take selfies right here looks good for
Instagram I also have three TVs here so
typically on one of the TV's I'll have a
movie or a game on this-tv I'll
typically have CNN or the news on that
TV I'll try to have either movie or
another game on or SportsCenter or
something like that you can always be
watching stuff I don't know why but I
love doing that while I live this is my
sound system crank music all the time
and then finally some nice window art
which I'll show you walking count
Garnett this is the world famous blue
lab owned by the glute guy this is my
blue lab I hope you enjoyed the doer